Raymond Pearl Papers ca.1895-1940 Mss.B.P312
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Hodge, C. F. (Box 12)
  - Hodson, Cora B. S. (Box 12)
  - Hoffman, Robert (Box 12)
  - Hofmann, Fred W. (Box 12)
  - Hogan, John F. (Box 12)
  - Hogstad, Anton, Jr. (Box 12)
  - Holland, Joseph W. (Box 12)
  - Holt, Henry and Company (Box 12)
  - Holzinger, C. (Box 12)
  - Holman, W. L. (Box 12)
  - Holt, Hamilton (Box 12)
  - Holzapfel, Ruth A. (Box 12)
  - Hooper, F. H. (Box 12)
    Encyclopaedia Britannica
  - Hoopes, Lillie G. (Box 12)
  - Hooten, Earnest A. (Box 12)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1917-1940; 21 items (Box 12)
    Biographical and personal data; Political issues; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; World War I -- Food Administration
  - Hoover War Library (Box 12)
  - Hopkins, Ernest Martin (Box 13)
  - Horner, Anton (Box 13)
  - Horton, Harold E. (Box 13)
  - Hotel Hershey (Box 13)
  - Hotelling, Harold (Box 13)
  - Howard, L. O. (Box 13)
  - Howard, William T., 1919-1939; 103 items (Box 13)
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Cancer, chemotherapy; Eugenics; Harvard University; Johns Hopkins University; Medical research; Political issues; Population, demography; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Howell, W. H. (Box 13)
  - Hrdlicka, Ales (Box 13)
  - Huber, Frederick R. (Box 13)
  - Huhn, Rudolf von, 1919-1929; 58 items (Box 13)
    Biographical and personal data; Business; Publication; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics
  - Hunt, Albert R. (Box 13)
  - Huntington, Edward V. (Box 13)
  - Huntington, Ellsworth (Box 13)
  - Hurd, Sarah Cooper (Box 13)
  - Hurd, William D. (Box 13)
  - Hurst, Fannie, 1923-1934; 46 items (Box 13)
    Biographical and personal data; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Hutchins, A. F. (Box 13)
  - Hutchins, Harry (Box 13)
  - Hutt, F. B. (Box 13)
  - Huxley, Julian S. (Box 13)
  - Hyatt, Edwin A. (Box 13)
  - Hyde, R. R. (Box 13)
  - Hyde Park Hotel, London (Box 13)
  - Iglehart, F. N., and Company (Box 13)
  - Ilsley, Morrill L. (Box 13)
  - Imai, Takeo (Box 13)
  - Indiana Banking Conference (Box 13)
    Greenough, Walter S.
    Myers, Robert H.
  - Indiana State Librarian (Box 13)
  - Indiana University, 1937-1940; 2 folders (61 items) (Box 13)
    Payne, Fernandus
    Wells, H. B.
    Elliott, Frank R.
    Bittner, W. S.
    Hall, Ford P.
    Saunders, Robert L.
    Moffat, James E.
    Biddle, W. G.
    Robinson, D. S.
    Willis, Hugh E.
    Indiana University--Patten Lectures; Lectures, public speaking; Recommendations; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Inge, William Ralph (Box 13)
  - Institut International De Statistique (Box 13)
  - Institute for Biological Research (Box 13)
    Jennings, Herbert S.
    Longcope, Warfield T.
  - International Association of Poultry Instructors and Investigators (Box 13)
    Brown, Edward
  - International Eugenics Congress, First (Box 13)
  - International Health Board (Box 13)
    Russell, Frederick F.
    Tisdale, W.
    Brierley, W. W.
  - International Institute of Statistics, 1937-1940; 11 folders (249 items) (Box 14)
    Barboza, Carneiro, J. A.
    Pietra, Gaetano
    Thege, Julius de Konkoly
    Willcox, Walter F.
    Stamp, Sir Josiah, Lord
    Flux, Sir Alfred W.
    Duggan, Stephen
    Julin, A. L. L. A.
    Mortara, Giorgio
    Verrijn Stuart, C. A.
    Hull, Cordell
    Phelps, E.
    Huber, M.
    Darmois, Georges
    Michalopoulos, Jean
    Angélopoulos, Angélos
    Davies, Joseph E.
    Craig, J. I.
    Hill, Joseph A.
    Fisher, Irving
    Political issues; Recommendations; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Agendas; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Committees; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Finances; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Minutes; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Newsletters; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs -- Statutes; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics
  - International Union for the Scientific Investigation of Population Problems, 1925-1939; 17 folders (398 items) (Box 14-15)
    Pitt-Rivers, George H. L. F.
    Close, Sir Charles
    Bojarquez, J. de D.
    Fischer, E.
    Rhodes, E. C.
    Landry, A.
    Kingsbury, John A.
    Mallet, Sir Bernard
    Dublin, Louis I.
    Cunard Line
    Regelink, Z., Jr.
    Molinari, A.
    Bernard, Leon
    Black, J. D.
    Mitchell, Wesley C.
    Amadeo, Tomas
    Coats, R. H.
    Mahaim, E.
    Mauco, Georges
    Whelpton, P. K.
    Little, C. C.
    American Birth Control League, Inc.
    Johnson, Beatrice W.
    Anthropology; Business; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Editorial matters; International Union for the Scientific Investigation of Population Problems; Political issues; Population, demography; Publication; Research support; Solicitations for support or contribution; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics
    - Folders 1-8 (Box 14)
    - Folders 9-11 (Box 15)
  - Ireland, Alleyne (Box 15)
  - Irving, Lawrence (Box 15)
  - Italy, Baltimore Consulate (Box 15)
    Papania, Antonio
    Cottafavi, Antonio
    Logoluso, Antonio
  - Iwanow, E. (Box 15)
  - Jackson, George S. (Box 15)
  - Jackson, Stuart W., 1934-1939; 56 items (Box 15)
    Biographical and personal data; Deafness; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - James, Olivia (Box 15)
    Kennedy, Walter P.
  - Janney, J. H. (Box 15)
  - Jastrow, Joseph (Box 15)
  - Jeanneney, G. (Box 15)
  - Jencks, Gardner (Box 15)
  - Jenkins, James Iredell (Box 15)
  - Jennings, Herbert Spencer, 1899-1929; 9 folders (249 items) (Box 15)
    Biron, Conrad J.
    Biographical and personal data; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Embryology, developmental genetics; Eugenics; Evolution; Fellowships, assistantships; Genetics; Graduate study -- University of Michigan; Johns Hopkins University; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Maine Agricultural Experiment Station; National Academy of Sciences; Pearson, Karl; Physiology; Poultry genetics; Protozoan genetics; Protozoology; Publication; Referee's report; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; United States Fish Commission; University of Pennsylvania; World War I -- Impact on science
  - Jenss, Rachel-M. (Box 15)
  - Jewett, F. B. (Box 15)
  - Johannsen, W. (Box 15)
    Johannsen, Elisabeth
  - Johns Hopkins University, 1919-1934; 3 folders (55 items) (Box 16)
    Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Johns Hopkins University -- Institute for Biological Research; Publication; Recommendations; Research support
    - Johns Hopkins University - Correspondence with Joseph S. Ames, 1919-1929 (Box 16)
      Cattell, James McKeen
      Yerkes, Robert M.
    - Johns Hopkins University - Correspondence with Frank J. Goodnow, 1919-1924 (Box 16)
    - Johns Hopkins University - Playshop, 1934 (Box 16)
  - Johnson, Alvin (Box 16)
  - Johnson, Douglas (Box 16)
  - Johnson, Gerald (Box 16)
  - Johnstone, James (Box 16)
  - Jones, Bassett, 1932-1940; 4 folders (105 items) (Box 16)
    Mills, Frederick C.
    Fisher, Arne
    Dubberstein, Waldo H.
    Conaut, Larry W.
    Cowles, Alfred, 3rd
    Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Economics; Educational matters; Political issues; Publication; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics
  - Jones, L. J. (Box 16)
  - Jones, T. W. (Box 16)
  - Jordan, H. E. (Box 16)
  - Journal Club (Box 16)
  - Kacprzak, M. (Box 16)
  - Kafemann, R. S. (Box 16)
  - Kalmus, Edwin F. (Box 16)
  - Kast, Ludwig (Box 16)
  - Katterfeld, L. E. (Box 16)
  - Kau, L. (Box 16)
  - Kauffman, C. H. (Box 16)
  - Kaunitz, Julius (Box 16)
  - Keen, W. W. (Box 16)
  - Keith, Arthur (Box 16)
  - Kelemen, Frank (Box 16)
  - Kelly, Fred C., 1919-1940; 4 folders (124 items) (Box 16)
    Casanova, Louis de
    Baker, William E., Jr.; Biographical and personal data; Business; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Stopes, Marie C.; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Kelly, Howard A. (Box 16)
  - Kelynack, T. N. (Box 16)
  - Kendall, Warren C. (Box 16)
    Hayward, Sidney Chandler
  - Kennard, T. and M. (Box 16)
  - Ketron, L. W. (Box 16)
  - Key, Helmer (Box 16)
  - Keyes, Homer Eaton (Box 16)
  - Kieffer, John E. (Box 16)
  - Kindler, Hans (Box 16)
  - King, Helen Dean (Box 16)
  - Kingsbury, John A. (Box 16)
  - Kinsey, Alfred (Box 16)
  - Kirchway, Freda (Box 16)
  - Kirkbride, Franklin B. (Box 16)
  - Klebs, Arnold C. (Box 16)
  - Kleeck, Mary Van (Box 16)
  - Van Kleeck, Mary (Box 16)
  - Klinefelter, Harry F. (Box 16)
  - Knauth, Oswald W. (Box 16)
  - Knibbs, Sir George H. (Box 16)
  - Knopf, Alfred (Box 16)
  - Knopf, S. Adolphus (Box 16)
  - Kofoid, C. A. (Box 16)
  - Kohler, Ineson (Box 16)
  - Kooiman, H. N. (Box 16)
  - Kopp, Marie E. (Box 16)
  - Korzybski, Alfred, 3 folders (Box 16)
    Trainor, Joseph C.
  - Kosswig, K. (Box 16)
  - Kostitzin, V. A. (Box 16)
  - Krebs, Sonnin (Box 16)
  - Kroeber, A. L. (Box 16)
  - Kronenberg, J. F. (Box 16)
  - Krutch, Joseph Wood (Box 17)
  - Kung, Hsien Wu (Box 17)
    Russell, H. L.
  - LaFarge, C. Grant (Box 17)
  - Lafleur, Laurence J. (Box 17)
  - La Gorce, John Oliver (Box 17)
  - Lancaster Press, Inc. (Box 17)
  - Lancet (Box 17)
  - Landauer, Walter (Box 17)
  - Landor, J. V. (Box 17)
    Edge, P. Granville
  - Lane, Gertrude B. (Box 17)
  - Langley, S. P. (Box 17)
  - Lankaster, E. Ray (Box 17)
  - Lantz, Walter D. - Dr. Raymond Pearl Library (Box 17)
  - Larkey, Sanford V. (Box 17)
  - Lashley, K. S. (Box 17)
  - Lawrence, Philip S. (Box 17)
  - Lawrence and Wishart Limited (Box 17)
  - Lazaron, Morris S. (Box 17)
  - Leach, L. (Box 17)
  - Leady, Agnes B. (Box 17)
  - Leavitt, Julian (Box 17)
  - Le Blanc, Thomas J., 1925-1933; 60 items (Box 17)
    Biochemistry and organic chemistry; Biographical and personal data; Conferences and symposia; Educational matters; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Medical research; Publication; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics -- Japan; Teaching; Travel -- Japan
  - Lee, Margaret L. (Box 17)
  - Leidy, Joseph (Box 17)
  - Leighton, J. and J., Limited (Box 17)
  - LeRiche, Harding (Box 17)
  - Leupold, Richard J. (Box 17)
  - Leventhal, Albert Rice (Box 17)
  - Lewis, A. Nelson (Box 17)
  - Lewis, Clarence (Box 17)
  - Lewis, Clarence McK. (Box 17)
  - Lewis, William Mather (Box 17)
  - Liebisch, Bernhard (Box 17)
  - Lillie, Frank R. (Box 17)
  - Lincoln, Leroy A. (Box 17)
  - Lindsey, Alton A. (Box 17)
  - Linn, W. C. A. (Box 17)
  - Lipschütz, A. (Box 17)
  - Livingston, Burton E. (Box 17)
  - Locke, C.E. Manufacturing Company (Box 17)
  - Lodge, Olive (Box 17)
  - Loeb, Jacques (Box 17)
  - Loeb, Leo (Box 17)
  - Logistic Curve (Box 17)
    Ulehla, Vladimir
    Davidson, James
    Lenovsky, Alan J.
  - Lorimer, Frank (Box 17)
  - Lotka, Alfred J., 1921-1940; 12 folders (318 items) (Box 17)
    Bailey, V. A.
    Close, C. F.
    Carr-Saunders, A. M.
    Kacprzak, Martin
    Johannsen, W.
    Anthropology; Bibliographical matters; Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Johns Hopkins University; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Physiology -- Longevity; Population, demography; Publication; Reviews; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics
  - Lovejoy, A. O. (Box 18)
  - Lowell, A. Lawrence (Box 18)
  - Ludwig, De H. (Box 18)
  - Lund, Frederick H. (Box 18)
  - Lundborg, H. (Box 18)
  - Lurman, Theodor G., Jr. (Box 18)
  - Lutz, Frank E. (Box 18)
  - M., P. (Box 18)
  - McAtee, Waldo L. (Box 18)
  - Macaulay, Fred R. (Box 18)
    Sprague, O. M. W.
  - McCarthy, Catherine (Box 18)
    Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc.
  - McClung, C. E. (Box 18)
  - McClure, Roy D. (Box 18)
  - McCollum, E. V. (Box 18)
  - MacDonald, Arthur (Box 18)
  - MacDuff, Douglas (Box 18)
  - McDuffee, Mrs. E. A. (Box 18)
  - McFall, R. J. (Box 18)
  - MacFarlane, Andrew (Box 18)
    Nelson, Thomas and Sons
  - McGuire, Constantine E. (Box 18)
  - McLanahan, Austin (Box 18)
  - Maclean, John (Box 18)
  - McMaster, W. H. (Box 18)
  - MacMillan Company (Box 18)
  - McMillan, James (Box 18)
  - McPherson, Clara L. (Box 18)
  - McQuiston, W. Carlton (Box 18)
  - Maguia, Sir Hiram (Box 18)
    Barr, Sir James
  - Malinowski, Bronislaw (Box 18)
  - Mallet, Lady (Box 18)
  - Mallet, Sir Bernard, 1927-1931; 14 folders (333 items) (Box 18)
    Crew, F. A. E.
    Gregory, J. W.
    Glazebrook, R. T.
    Tait, D. Christie
    Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Gini, Corrado; International Union for the Scientific Investigation of Population Problems; National Research Council; Wilson, Edwin Bidwell
  - Malloch, Archibald (Box 18)
  - Maloevf, N. S. (Box 18)
  - Manca, G. (Box 18)
  - Mank, Edith Webster (Box 18)
  - Mann, Lucille (Box 18)
  - Mann, W. W. (Box 18)
  - Marburg, Theodore (Box 18)
  - Marchant, Sir James (Box 18)
  - Mark, E. L. (Box 19)
  - Markel, Lester (Box 19)
  - Marshall, L. C. (Box 19)
  - Marshall, William (Box 19)
  - Martin, J. Holmes (Box 19)
    Poultry Science Association
    Thompson, R. B.
  - Maryland Academy of Sciences (Box 19)
    Woodfield, Frank A.
  - Maryland Club (Box 19)
  - Mason, Max (Box 19)
  - Maternity Center Association (Box 19)
  - Meidell, Birger (Box 19)
  - Mells, Eder Y. De (Box 19)
  - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1923-1948; 15 folders (509 items) (Box 19)
    Werner, W. L.
    Bartlett, George W.
    Chambers, Benjamin F.
    Brandl, D.
    Phil
    American Mercury
    Brin, Joseph G.
    Sister Anthony
    Johnson, Rev. Hannibal S.
    Jacob, Fred
    Burns, Ellen
    Angoff, Charles
    Lustgarten, Edith
    Whiting, Leon F.
    Baker, Frederick A.
    Obituary of Raymond Pearl
    Biographical and personal data; Evolution -- Scopes trial; Political issues; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Mendenhall, T. C. (Box 20)
  - Merant, G. M. (Box 20)
  - Merriam, John C. (Box 20)
  - Merritt-Hawkes, Mrs. O. A. (Box 20)
  - "Metron" (Box 20)
    Galvani, Luigi
    Orlandi, Silvio
  - Metropolitan Life Insurance Company (Box 20)
    Bradley, Florence
    Ecker, Frederick H.
    Conarroe, E. H.
  - Mettee, Andrew H. (Box 20)
  - Metz, Charles W. (Box 20)
  - Meyer, Adolf (Box 20)
  - Meyers, Charles F. (Box 20)
  - Miani, D. (Box 20)
  - Michigan Alumnus (Book Orders) (Box 20)
  - Michelson, A. A. (Box 20)
  - Migration. Notes (Box 20)
  - Milbank, Albert (Box 20)
  - Miller, Dayton C. (Box 20)
  - Miller, Herbert Adolphus (Box 20)
  - Miller, Iva (Box 20)
  - Miller, S. R. (Box 20)
  - Millikan, R. A. (Box 20)
  - Mills, J. J. (Box 20)
  - Miner, John R. (Box 20)
    Machen, Arthur W.
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 20)
  - "Mr. Peabody is Puzzled" (Box 20)
  - Mjoen, Jan Alfred (Box 20)
  - Mockeridge, Florence A. (Box 20)
  - Moffett, W. Edwin (Box 20)
  - Mollison, Th. (Box 20)
  - Mondolf, A. (Box 20)
  - Money, Sir Leo Chiozza (Box 20)
  - Montagu, Ashley (Box 20)
  - Moore, J. Percy (Box 20)
  - Moran, S. A. (Box 20)
  - Morgan, O. S. (Box 20)
  - Morgan, Thomas Hunt, 1911-1931; 3 folders (64 items) (Box 20)
    Brockett, Paul
    Columbia University; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Editorial matters; Laboratory techniques, equipment; National Academy of Sciences; Physiology; Publication; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Shull, George Harrison; Solicitations for support or contribution; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Morris, Mrs. Roland S. (Box 20)
  - Morse, Gertrude Davis (Box 20)
  - Morse, W. J. (Box 20)
  - Mortality and Morbitity (Box 20)
  - Mortara, Giorgio (Box 20)
    Kittredge, Tracy B.
  - Morton, Dudley J. (Box 20)
  - Mudgett, Bruce D. (Box 20)
  - Munson, W. H. (Box 20)
  - Munzer, Fr. Th. (Box 20)
    Hecht, John
    Hibbetts, Augusta K.
  - Mullenix, Rollin C. (Box 20)
  - Murbach, Louis (Box 20)
  - Murphy, Douglas P. (Box 20)
  - Murphy, Henry A. (Box 20)
  - Murphy, Ruth (Box 20)
  - Murray, Cecil D. (Box 20)
  - Murray, George R. (Box 20)
  - Murray, Harry (Box 20)
  - Murray, Henry A. (Box 20)
  - Murray, John (Box 20)
  - Murray, John G., Jr. (Box 20)
  - Murray, Thomas C. (Box 20)
  - Museum of Comparative Zoology (Box 20)
  - Musselman, J. R. (Box 20)
  - Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York (Box 20)
    Foshay, P. Maxwell
  - Myslivec, Vaclav (Box 20)
  - Nachtsheim, Hans (Box 20)
  - Nakamura, Kaju (Box 20)
  - Nation (Box 20)
    Mussey, Henry Raymond
    Hazlitt, Henry
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1919-1924; 4 folders (135 items) (Box 20)
    Day, Arthur L.
    Noyes, W. A.
    Bingham, Harold C.
    Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Editorial matters; Educational matters; Genetics; National Research Council; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1 (Box 20)
    - Folder 2 (Box 20)
    - Folder 3 (Box 20)
    - Folder 4 (Box 20)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1927-1933; 3 folders (85 items) (Box 21)
    White, Walter F.
    Niles, Walter L.
    Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Human evolution, physical anthropology -- Race; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - National Library of Peiping (Box 21)
  - National Research Council, 1923-1925; 3 folders (57 items) (Box 21)
    Yule, J. H. J.
    Biographical and personal data; Committee activities; Editorial matters; Laboratory techniques, equipment; National Academy of Sciences; Publication; Requests for aid in finding positions; Research support; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics
  - Neal, H. V. (Box 21)
  - Neisskopf, J. (Box 21)
  - Nelson, Louise A. (Box 21)
  - Netusil, F. J. (Box 21)
  - New York Academy of Medicine (Box 21)
  - New York Times (Box 21)
  - Newsholme, Sir Arthur (Box 21)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 21)
  - Niceforo, A. (Box 21)
  - Nickerson, Hoffman (Box 21)
  - Nicoll, Matthias (Box 21)
  - Niles, Henry E. (Box 21)
  - Nock, Albert Jay (Box 21)
  - Nock, Arthur D. (Box 21)
  - Obituaries (Box 21)
  - O'Connor, Basil (Box 21)
  - Ogburn, William F. (Box 21)
  - Ogden, C. K. (Box 21)
  - "Old People should not be allowed to Vote" Speech (Box 21)
  - Oliphant, Herman (Box 21)
  - Oliver, James (Box 21)
  - Orton, Lawrence M. (Box 21)
  - Osborn, Henry Fairfield (Box 21)
  - Osborne, Carl N. (Box 21)
  - Owens, Hamilton (Box 21)
    Wagner, Philip M.
    Owens, Olga
  - Packer, Gilbert (Box 21)
  - Page, Walter H. (Box 21)
  - Park, Edwards A. (Box 21)
  - Park, Thomas (Box 21)
  - Parker, G. H. (Box 21)
  - Parker, John H. (Box 21)
  - Parker, Sylvia L. (Box 21)
  - Parkes, A. L. (Box 21)
  - Parrish, H. (Box 21)
  - Parshley, Howard Madison (Box 21)
  - Passport (Box 21)
  - Paszkiewicz, Ludwik (Box 21)
  - Paton, Stewart (Box 21)
  - Patten, William (Box 21)
  - Peabody Conservatory of Music (Box 21)
    Baker, Mary S.
  - Peard, F. Furnival (Box 21)
  - Pearl, Frank (Box 21)
  - Pearl, Leslie G. (Box 21)
  - Pearl, Penelope M., 1930-1942; 40 items (Box 21)
    Yule, G. Udley
    Pearl, Ruth D.
    Biographical and personal data; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Pearl, Raymond, 7 folders (Box 21)
    - "Funeral Discourse", n.d.; 1 folder (Box 21)
    - Identification Book (British), 1918; 1 folder (Box 21)
    - Letters to Robert Yerkes, 1904; 1 folder (Box 21)
    - Memorial Dinner, 1941; 1 folder (Box 21)
    - "No Ballot for Aged" (Speech --replies), 1939-1940; 1 folder (Box 21)
    - "Plan for Research on the Biology of Life Duration and Extension", 1 folder (Box 21)
    - Sale of Library, 1941; 1 folder (Box 21)
  - Pearl, Roswell T. (Box 22)
  - Pearl, Ruth DeWitt (Box 22)
  - Pearson, Karl, 1901-1937; 6 folders (141 items) (Box 22)
    Pearson, Margaret V.
    Elderton, Ethel M.
    Biographical and personal data; Botany and plant genetics; Committee activities; Congratulations, greetings, thanks; Editorial matters; Eugenics; Fellowships, assistantships; Genetics; Human evolution, physical anthropology; Human genetics; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Maine Agricultural Experiment Station; Poultry genetics; Publication; Reviews; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Teaching -- University of London; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
  - Pearson, Karl -- Pearl Correspondence, Pearson Papers, University College, London [copies], 1903-1932; 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Pearson, Maria S. (Box 22)
  - Penniman, T. K. (Box 22)
  - Penniman, W. B. D. (Box 22)
  - Perkins, Eben F. (Box 22)
    Roberts, J. A. Drasea
    Cobb, W. Montague
    Perkins, Harry F.
    Reed, Towell D.
    Hernando, Eugenio
  - Perley, C. A. (Box 22)
  - Peterson, Houston (Box 22)
  - Petrunkevitch, Alexander (Box 22)
  - Phillips, A. G. (Box 22)
  - Phillips, John C. (Box 22)
  - Photoplay (Box 22)
  - Piddington, R. A. (Box 22)
  - Pinchot, Cornelia Bryce (Box 22)
  - Pitt-Rivers, George H. L. F. (Box 22)
  - Pincus, Gregory (Box 22)
  - Pithotomy (Box 22)
  - Place cards (Box 22)
  - Plan for Research on the Biology of Life Duration and Extension (Box 22)
  - Plate, Ludwig (Box 22)
  - Platt, Gordon J. (Box 22)
  - Polignac, Marquis M. De (Box 22)
  - Pontifical College Josephinum (Box 22)
  - Pooler, Miss Blanche (Box 22)
  - Popoff, Dr. (Box 22)
  - Population Association of America, 1934-1936; 2 folders (61 items) (Box 22)
    Lorimer, Frank
    Baker, O. E.
    Latimer, H. B.
    Lotka, Alfred J.
    Committee activities; Conferences and symposia; Political issues; Population, demography; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Porter, Georgia P. (Box 22)
  - Porter, W. T. (Box 22)
  - Potter, George F. (Box 22)
  - Potts, F. A. (Box 22)
  - Poultry Science Association (Box 22)
    Maw, W. A.
    Leite De Castro, Christovam
  - Powell, Frederic H. (Box 22)
  - Power, D'Arcy (Box 22)
  - Prather, William L. (Box 22)
  - Pratt, Joseph H. (Box 22)
  - Prechtl, John (Box 22)
  - Prentiss, C. W. (Box 22)
  - Prokop, Peter (Box 22)
  - Putter, August (Box 22)
  - Punnett, R. C. (Box 22)
  - Pusey, William Allen (Box 22)
  - Putnam, Persis (Box 22)
  - Quarterly Review of Biology, 1927-1940; 3 folders (47 items) (Box 22)
    Lashley, K. S.
    Kroeber, A. L.
    Ruthven, Alexander G.
    Merriam, John C.
    Weed, Lewis H.
    Parker, G. H.
    Conklin, E. G.
    Buros, Oscar K.
    Van Straelen, V.
    Bailey, J. W.
    Metz, C. V. O.
    Wheeler, W. M.
    Kraatz, Walter C.
    Gill, Robert S.
    Harrison, Ross G.
    Hegner, Robert
    Lillie, Frank R.
    Morris, Charles W.
    Committee activities -- Advisory board; Editorial matters; Publication -- Quarterly Review of Biology
  - Quattrone, F. (Box 22)
  - Quirk, James R. (Box 22)
  - Radcliffe, George (Box 22)
  - Rajchman, Ludwik (Box 22)
  - Ramon y Cajal, S. (Box 22)
  - Randall, Blanchard (Box 22)
  - Rashevsky, N. (Box 22)
  - Rav, Phil (Box 22)
  - Raymond, Alice (Box 22)
  - Redfield, Alfred C. (Box 22)
  - Reed, Howard S. (Box 22)
  - Reed, Lowell J. (Box 22)
  - Reed, Walter (Box 23)
  - Reighard, Jacob (Box 23)
  - Research and Training in the Department of Biology... with special Reference to Human Biology (Box 23)
  - Research Council on Problems of Alcohol (Box 23)
    Lewis, C.
    James, J. H.
    Worsley, S. J.
    University of London
    Bowman, Karl M.
    Moore, Merrill
  - Rice, John L. (Box 23)
  - Rice, Stuart A. (Box 23)
  - Richards, Oscar W. (Box 23)
  - Richardson, Russell (Box 23)
  - Richter (Box 23)
  - Richter, Curt P. (Box 23)
  - Rigiu, Giulio (Box 23)
  - Rignano, Eugenio (Box 23)
  - Riley, C. F. Curtis (Box 23)
  - Rimsky-Korsakoff, V. N. (Box 23)